CURRICULAM VITAE

Mohammed Hassain

Content Design Lead

Curriculum Vitae



Mohammed Hassain

Content Design Lead

+ 91 70199 30394

hassain07@gmail.com



Bangalore Karnataka





Experienced and highly skilled Content Design Lead with a creative flair and a multitude of talents. With over a 10 years of experience in managing Creative, Print media, and Operations teams, I bring a wealth of knowledge to the table. As a reliable and skilled Graphic Designer and Video Developer/Editor, I possess expertise in all aspects of creative content design. With a commitment to delivering top-notch quality

Education



Bachelor In Applied Commerce

IVUP College Bangalore, Karnataka

Pre-University

ICPEM School of Higher Grade Qualification Bangalore, Karnataka

Diploma In Graphic Design (Desktop Publishing)

Mega Infotech Computers Education Society Bangalore, Karnataka

Diploma In Computer Application

Mega Infotech Computers Education Society Bangalore, Karnataka

Software's Expertise



- Ps Adobe Illustrator
- Ai Adobe Photoshop
- Adobe InDesign
- Pr Adobe Premiere Pro
- Ae Adobe After Effects
- Au Adobe Audition
- Me Adobe Media Encoder
- Xd Adobe XD
- Corel Draw
- Canva

Microsoft PowerPoint

×∄

Microsoft Excel

W

Microsoft Word

9

Google Slides

Google Sheet Google Docs

Google Forms

®

ChatGPT

Al

AI Tools

Work Experience



Content Design Lead

Udaan.com | Jan 2019 - July 2022 | Bangalore

- Creating and executing diverse static and dynamic content for L&D teams.
- Crafting captivating content and visuals, encompassing Instructional Presentations, Logos, Brand Identity, Posters, Social media posts, Instructional training videos, and basic Motion graphics.
- Developing storyboards and scripts for training content, overseeing LMS management, and ensuring the smooth operation of the content knowledge portal.
- Efficiently managing and leading a graphic design team, coordinating with the Training team, Voiceover artists, and stakeholders for seamless collaboration.

Production Manager

My Print 247 | Sep 2016 - Sep 2017 | Bangalore

- Taking charge as the leader of a dynamic Graphic Design and Print Production team.
- Crafting bespoke creatives tailored to meet client's specific requirements.
- Expertly managing end-to-end operations processes for creative design and print production.

Operations Manager and Creative Coordinator

Beyond Events and Exhibition Pvt Ltd | May 2014 - August 2016 | Bangalore

- Taking charge as the leader of a dynamic Graphic Design and Print Production team.
- Taking the helm in designing captivating graphics and visuals for all event-related materials.
- Ensuring timely delivery of projects while maintaining client satisfaction through exceptional results.

Production Manager

Creative Inn | June 2011 - April 2014 | Bangalore

- Unleashing creativity to design captivating visuals for diverse types of events.
- Overseeing print production processes to ensure timely delivery of high-quality deliverables.
- Expertly managing corporate events and ensuring seamless execution and impactful results.

Languages



English

Kannada

Hindi

Urdu

Tamil

Interest



Body building Listening Music Art/Sketch

Personal Skills



Designing

Leadership

Team Work

Management

Creativity

Personal Details



Age : 30

Gender : Male

Maritial Status : Single

THANK YOU